<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jingwei&#39;s</title>
    <link>http://leijingwei.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jingwei&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright [Jingwei&#39;s](https://leijingwei.com)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:03:47 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://leijingwei.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://leijingwei.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 09:19:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leijingwei.com/about/</guid>
      <description>啥人 总结起来就是一个在家带娃炒股养家糊口的人。
啥经历 入市8年了，4年亏，1年平，最近3年赚。
尼日利亚呆过两年，大市场小地摊都去过。
通信voip老兵，手里有95资质，靠这个赚了第一桶金。
码农，学艺不精的那种，只靠这门收益吃过点闲散饭。
啥想法 以后炒股养家，等孩子上幼儿园后，发现机会再去创业折腾，折腾的钱从股市盈余里出，折腾回来的钱又投入股市。
我的联系方式  雪球：https://xueqiu.com/u/realinvestor 微信：juejindys 公众号咱也有，自己搜索“掘金大元帅”  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 8.3 升级默认 nginx</title>
      <link>http://leijingwei.com/posts/nginx-update-centos8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:03:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leijingwei.com/posts/nginx-update-centos8/</guid>
      <description>先添加中科大的仓库 vim /etc/yum.repos.d/nginx.repo 里面的内容如下：
[nginx-mainline] name=nginx mainline repo baseurl=http://mirrors.ustc.edu.cn/nginx/mainline/centos/$releasever/$basearch/ gpgcheck=0 enabled=1 module_hotfixes=true 升级 yum update nginx 查看nginx版本 nginx -v </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>博客开篇</title>
      <link>http://leijingwei.com/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:02:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leijingwei.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>想了很久，还是决定重新开始写博客。有些东西还是不适合写在朋友圈，索性写在这里，把关于生活、投资、编程的点滴都记录下来。
博客建立的过程 我使用的是阿里云的轻服务器，香港地区的，环境是CentOS Linux release 8.3.2011版本，域名本来是我的个人域名，后来用公司的名义备案了，之所以选香港的服务器，还是因为国内确实有些东西不能写，用香港的会好很多，而且很多github上的东西用香港的服务器下载起来更快。
因为对网站的功能要求不多，纯粹是一个自己写自己看的博客，所以直接选用了生成静态网页最快的hugo来生成网站，以前我习惯用hexo，但说实话，速度实在让人受不了，hugo的速度还是杠杠的，我很满意。至于主题我用的是 ink ,个人觉得还是比较符合我的审美。
我原本计划用github pages的，但是速度真的很慢，所以搞了个服务器。也不贵，一个月才24元。我将代码上传的github作为中转，而不是直接将本地代码传到服务器，主要是为了避免我本地有时候错误直接上传到服务器会导致网站down机。
我还添加了Google Analytics来分析网站的流量，其实没什么用，反正大部分访问估计也是自己在看。
就这样，一个简单的博客就建立了。
写点什么 由于已经很久没有写代码了，有些命令什么的也比较生疏了，所以写博客的目的很大程度是为了自己方便记录一些文章，方便自己下次用的时候找起来方便。
另一个原因就是我2020年在家带孩子，也被动的成为了一个专业的投资者了，也确实需要一个网站或者博客来写写文章，记录记录自己投资体系建立的过程，回顾回顾自己的交易历史，写写个股的分析，供自己事后回顾。
上面两个大概就是我博客的主要内容了，希望能一直坚持下去。
不用公众号的原因 其实我雪球和公众号的粉丝加起来也有上万人了，但说实话，大部分写公众号的大v们目的和动机都是不纯的，我自然不屑于赚这份钱，做投资还是纯粹点好。
祝大家安好！ </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Syntax Guide</title>
      <link>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to test dark mode?</title>
      <link>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 12:13:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-7/</guid>
      <description>You can set dark mode as default by setting params.mode to dark in config.toml or set it to auto which will detect based on your OS and switch to dark mode. For more details refer documentation
Here is how you can switch based on your OS
 iOS Android macOS Windows 10  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography</title>
      <link>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 12:13:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-5/</guid>
      <description>Lid est laborum et dolorum fuga. Et harum quidem rerum facilis est et expeditasi distinctio. Nam libero tempore, cum soluta nobis est eligendi optio cumque nihilse impedit quo minus id quod amets untra dolor amet sad. Sed ut perspser iciatis unde omnis iste natus error sit voluptatem accusantium doloremque laste. Dolores sadips ipsums sits.
Heading 1 Lid est laborum et dolorum fuga. Et harum quidem rerum facilis est et expeditasi distinctio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Traveling Ultralight</title>
      <link>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 12:13:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-4/</guid>
      <description>I’m on a trip at the moment, and a friend who generously let me sleep on his couch looked at my small travel backpack and commented on how little I travel with: “That’s impressive,” he said.
I was a little surprised, because though I’ve gotten that comment before, it’s become normal for me to travel with just a small bag (10 lbs. or less, usually), and I have friends who travel with even less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Learned to Stop Procrastinating, &amp; Love Letting Go</title>
      <link>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 12:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-3/</guid>
      <description>The end of procrastination is the art of letting go.
I’ve been a lifelong procrastinator, at least until recent years. I would put things off until deadline, because I knew I could come through. I came through on tests after cramming last minute, I turned articles in at the deadline after waiting until the last hour, I got things done.
Until I didn’t. It turns out procrastinating caused me to miss deadlines, over and over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fearlessness: How to Stop Running from Space</title>
      <link>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 12:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-2/</guid>
      <description>We spend our days filling in every available space, cramming in more tasks, responding to messages, checking social media and online sites, watching videos.
We are afraid of empty space in our lives.
The result is often a continual busyness, constant distraction and avoidance, lack of focus, lack of satisfaction with our lives.
We run from silence. We run from the spaces between tasks and appointments. We run from solitude and stillness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primer: When You Have Too Much to Do</title>
      <link>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leijingwei.com/posts/post-1/</guid>
      <description>You have a to-do list that scrolls on for days. You are managing multiple projects, getting lots of email and messages on different messaging systems, managing finances and personal health habits and so much more.
It all keeps piling up, and it can feel overwhelming.
How do you keep up with it all? How do you find focus and peace and get stuff accomplished when you have too much on your plate?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
